<?xml version='1.0' ?>

<!-- <!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oa
sis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd"[]> -->
<!-- This comment is meant to settle gvim -->

<chapter id="learning">
<title>How to Learn Perl</title>

<para>
In order to effectively use this reference, you need to be familiar with 
some common Perl basics and pitfalls. Teaching Perl is out of the scope of
this document, but nonetheless, in this section we will refer you to 
common ways in which you can learn Perl.
</para>

<para>
One note is in order: Perl is positively <emphasis>huge</emphasis>
and most tutorials and books cover only a subset of it to get going. As a 
result, you may find yourself suffering from the "for someone who only has 
a hammer, everything looks like a nail" syndrome. That is, you will try to 
achieve everythings using only the elements you've learned, and will still 
not have the tools to write professional Perl programs, much less read the 
code of experts.
</para>

<section id="installing">

<title>Installing Perl</title>

<para> 
To get started using Perl, you should install it on your machine, so you
can play with it. The first chapter of Simon Cozens' book <ulink
url="http://learn.perl.org/library/beginning_perl/">Beginning Perl</ulink>
covers the basics of installing Perl on the most common systems.  
</para>

</section> <!-- End of Installation Section -->

<section id="learning_learning">

<title>Learning Perl</title>

<para>
There are chiefly two ways to learn how to program Perl: from online resources
or by reading a book.
</para>

<para>
There are several online resources that give a list of tutorials to learn
Perl from. One of them is the <ulink url="http://perl-begin.berlios.de/tutorials/">Perl Beginners' Site Online Tutorials Section</ulink>. Another, which is
more encompassing, but less organized and descriptive is 
<ulink url="http://dmoz.org/Computers/Programming/Languages/Perl/FAQs,_Help,_and_Tutorials/">the relevant category from the Open Directory Project</ulink>.
</para>

<para>
<ulink url="http://learn.perl.org/library/beginning_perl/">
The online version of Simon Cozens' Beginning Perl</ulink> book is probably 
the most comprehensive tutorial available. If you wish to get started even more
quickly then you can try (at your own risk) a different tutorial listed in
the resources above.
</para>

<para>
If you wish to purchase or borrow a book that will guide you through the
first steps in Perl, then the <ulink url="http://books.perl.org/category/7">Beginner Books category of the Perl Books site</ulink> should be of help. It 
contains ratings, reviews, information and links about the commonly available
books.
</para>

<section id="internationalized">

<title>Resources in Foreign Languages</title>

<para>
The French Perl Mongers (Perl mongers are Perl user groups around the globe) 
wrote an <ulink url="http://lea-linux.org/dev/perl.php3">introduction to 
Perl</ulink> in French. Semeul Vomberg wrote a <ulink url="http://code.semuel.co.il/perlhebtut/index.html">Hebrew Tutorial for Perl</ulink>.
</para>
</section> <!-- End of Internationalized Learning Section -->
</section> <!-- End of the Learning Section -->
</chapter>

<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
mode: xml
sgml-omittag:nil
sgml-shorttag:nil
sgml-namecase-general:nil
sgml-general-insert-case:lower
sgml-minimize-attributes:nil
sgml-always-quote-attributes:t
sgml-indent-step:4
sgml-indent-data:t
sgml-exposed-tags:nil
sgml-local-catalogs:nil
sgml-local-ecat-files:nil
sgml-parent-document: "fcs_arch_doc.xml"
End:
vim:indentexpr=:
-->
